[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
I'm not sure I really WANT
redemption from electro-Jesus.
I mean, what kind of electric sins
is he going to forgive me for?
Too much resistance?
The human body doesn't use THAT much power.
What's the brain? 20 watts?
Something like that?
Okay, I guess we DID use a lot of
power conducting the experiment,
and that sort of ended the world.
So, yeah, I guess that one's on me.
[zombie growls]
Hup!
I'm pretty sure that's not even why people
want to kill me, though. I'm just...here.
I mean, we're talking different levels--
Dammit.
--different levels of wanting to kill me.
[straining]
Obviously the people in this town
want to kill me for different reasons
than in the city. I'm multicultural.
Wow, so that was really it. He was
blocking the way with his corpse fire.
Why?
It doesn't scare them off.
It was just a propane tank;
it was going to burn out by morning.
That makes no sense if
you're not having a concert.
[loud explosion]
WOW!
Making my OWN music.
Well, not really.
That would be better as a support.
Like, you wait for a break in the song,
then blow up the barrel as it comes back.
[imitating guitar riff]
Explosion.
My talent's wasted here.
Just like the propane.
Though, there IS a lot
of fuel in these parts.
See? European Saudi Arabia.
[loud explosion]
Whoa!
Yeah, I'm making a lot of noise.
But why are they...
Why are they leaving fuel
drums in tight hallways?
Another one!
Okay, good.
I wouldn't want--Are you KIDDING me?
Jesus Christ!
Well, I guess that would be a quick death.
I pull the trigger, my aim's sloppy,
a few milliseconds of a flash, then death?
I mean, they had to
cart the barrels up here.
That's a lot of work for...no reason at all.
Oh what, is he faking?
OH!
BASTARD!
Can't assume a thing.
So are they learning, or just lazy?
I guess that's more positive than
being pissed off all the time.
Oh no...
So do I need to worry about you?
Yeah, just lying there, huh?
OH MY GOD!
I'M OUT!
Okay, so is this going to be a thing now?
I have to shoot every
single body, just in case?
That's who I am? I'm that guy now?
That's not who I am. I don't
have that kind of ammo.
[poison headcrab rattles, hisses]
What the fuck?
Like a rattlesnake.
Holy shit!
Nawww...
Oh, good! They understand what I'm saying!
Yeah, that's what was missing from my life--
for these things to look more like
black widow spiders, and hiss at me.
That really filled the void.
I guess this is a good day after all.
Oh, so HERE'S the sw...
Wait, did I turn it off?
It stopped sparking, but
that doesn't mean it's off.
I'm going to get out of
here before I start a fire.
Though fires are less scary
when it's not YOUR house,
so you don't care if it burns down.
I'm not attached to this place.
And neither was the owner. Maybe
that's why there were fuel drums here.
Maybe the invasion interrupted an
insurance scam from a decade or two ago.
There's not really--OH!
Where are they coming from?
Oh, they must've been hiding in the
generators, and I walked right by them.
I can't b--OH MY GOD!
No! I need you to promise me
you'll never do that again.
Can you do that?
Okay, I think I believe you.
This is a trust exercise.
This is me trusting you.
On second thought, you were
making that hissing noise,
and I think we both know that's not cool.
So, sorry, you failed the
exercise. This is on you.
Still kind of weird how
they drop down, though.
Wow, they can't fly, can they?
That would make the day
worse. More than a little bit.
It's always something.
I still don't know if I
even need to go this way.
Yeah, if somebody could see me,
they might ask why am I breaking
into a transformer station,
and I would say,
"Fuck you. Why do anything?"
Looks safe...
Yeah, don't think they'd
have an answer for that.
Yeah, it feels impossible, but
today actually could've been worse.
During that nightmare this morning,
I could've been teleported into a building
and had my neck snapped.
And we still don't even know
what caused the FIRST cascade.
Maybe my body could've just
kept teleporting forever.
I would've become a real-life haunting,
because no one would ever know
when my body would show up.
[man laughs maniacally]
Ah ha ha ha ha ha...
MAN: Well done, brother!
Oh, you were watching.
MAN: Make free use of my traps, but
take care not to fall in them yourself.
Call me Mr. Trapeze.
MAN: Behind you!
What?!
Where?
OH!
MAN: In Ravenholm, you'd
do well to be vigilant.
The roof!
Oh my god, this is embarrassing.
Now he thinks I'm wet behind the ears.
NYAH!
I made TWO mistakes! Right in front of him!
First mistake: I'm getting sloppy.
I forgot that anything could kill
me from anywhere at all times.
What's wrong with me?
I don't get shot at for ten
minutes and now I'm turning soft?
How many of these hunters
are dropping from above?
It feels like a lot lately.
Second mistake: He had a gun on
me, and I turned my back to him.
He said, "Behind you!"
I actually fell for that!
That's something *I* would say!
He may as well have told me my shoes
are untied! That's Looney Tunes shit!
Okay, I need to land on the support
in case the boards are loose
so they don't catapult
and smack me in the face.
I bet he's filming this,
just in case I faceplant.
Probably using a fisheye lens, too.
Then he narrates it, saying,
"Watch out for the traps."
Then the music starts.
[humming bass line]
How is that guy living here?
I mean...
I can see passing through, but in
SOME ways, this is worse than fleas.
There's no--OH!
Actually fleas are not mutually
exclusive to this situation.
Is he trying to wait them out?
Yeah, just what's going on here?
How are they sustaining themselves?
All I'm seeing are predators.
I'm out!
I mean, okay, they ate everyone in town;
I haven't seen any dogs or
cats--they probably ate them, too;
at some point, this party is going to end.
Maybe he's counting on that.
We're still in the honeymoon phase
while there's corpses lying around.
[grunting]
But, eventually...
...they're going to run out
of things to eat.
Honestly, I'm doing them
a favor by shooting them.
Now they have a fresh supply to cannibalize.
You're welcome.
I'm probably prolonging
all of this by months.
What is this?
Pull lever.
OH!
ATTACK OF THE K-CARS!
NOT AGAIN!
Wait, no, that's a European.
Okay...
Fuck.
Well, so much for a quiet night.
MAN: Better and better!
Okay, he is definitely filming me.
I don't see the cameras, but
there's a lot of places to put them.
Oh, and of course. I'm in the
future. Who knows what they have now?
They could have fiber optics all
over here and I wouldn't see a thing.
Oh! Maybe that's how they were tracking me!
I hope he's not broadcasting this.
Of course I'll look good on camera,
but if the cops see me, then...
They might just bomb the town.
Or just drop nerve gas. That would be great.
Please back up.
Beep. Beep.
Okay, let's do it.
Huh. Well. That DID work,
but I can't imagine something less
efficient without going full Rube Goldberg.
But then that's not the point, is it?
The point is,
this guy saw "The Running Man",
and now he's living his dream through me.
I get it now.
Though this doesn't look developed
into a full game show yet.
He must still be working on it.
Hup!
So my appearance was just a
lucky coincidence for him.
So he's having me trial run his
course before he goes public.
That's good, because that means
he's probably NOT broadcasting this,
since it's not fit for presentation yet.
He needs lights, music... probably
has to do a bunch of painting.
So where the hell am I going?
He needs to work on that.
Yeah, I was giving him a 50-50 chance
he was just going to keep these videos
for his private collection anyway.
He seems like the type.
So where does he expect me to go?
Those catwalks are obviously
part of the course.
Oh! It's like the old saying...
"When is a car like an elevator?
"Pretty much only this time ever."
This is so inefficient.
Could be worse.
I think he took out the engine block.
GRIGORI: I am Father Grigori.
Wah!
GRIGORI: You have already
met--heh heh--my "congregation".
[Grigori laughs maniacally]
[laughing maniacally]
Damn, I don't remember the
ending to The Running Man.
I know there were people trying to
kill him that were part of the show,
but I can't remember if it was
rigged for him to lose or not.
I kind of want to know that
considering my situation.
That guy's probably seen
the movie a hundred times.
I mean, he's taking some
creative liberties, but...
Now I wonder how many
aliens were actually here,
or if he was just trucking them all in.
[shotgun blasts, Grigori laughing]
So does he want to be the
contestant or the host?
Sounds like both.
FUCKING HELL!
GRIGORI: Woe betide--
[loud sigh]
Oh my god... I heard that one...
Almost took my head off.
And I can't believe I'm saying this,
but I think that was an accident?
Yeah, he's not firing.
Yeah, you're not trying to kill me,
you're just not worried about any of
that "in the line of fire" bullshit, huh?
GRIGORI: Ah! It is you, brother.
I apologize.
GRIGORI: But, no harm done.
Ehhh...
GRIGORI: My bullets are
the least of your concerns.
No...
No, don't sell yourself short.
You--oh, he's gone.
You're right that you're
not my BIGGEST concern,
but that little st--
[Grigori laughs]
Oh, so he CAN hear me. Well then...
What the fuck?!
AS I WAS SAYING!
That potshot promoted you
from least of my concerns.
Give yourself some credit.
OH! PERFECT!
JUST WHO I WANT TO SEE--
Wait, what the fuck? You're back?
Are you aiming at me when I turn?
Wait! What was that?! What
was THAT fucking motion?!
You'd better not take another shot at me!
AH?!
That's what I thought!
I think this guy might be
hearing voices or something.
JEE!
OH YOU WANT SOME?!
[loud explosion]
Oh, that's loud...
So much for lying low.
I tried.
[loud explosion]
Yep. Yep...
[multiple loud explosions]
Yeah, that should let
everyone know where I am.
Any helicopters?
No? Eh, it'll probably
take them a few minutes.
I'm still not sure if this
guy's trying to kill me or not.
I think he might not be sure either.
Maybe the voices can't decide.
What he DOES understand is if you're going
to shoot the king, you'd better not miss.
Come on. Quit crawling around.
Wow, the car's still burning.
Yeah, you should be able to
see this from the air nicely.
At least it's overcast. That
should block me from satellites.
Or MOST satellites!
Yeah, dammit, I can't assume anything.
I don't know what technology they have.
Yeah, wasn't there a Star Trek episode where some
guy goes to the future, tries to scam people,
but then his ass gets busted because he
doesn't realize what he's up against?
The fucking future, man...
I don't even know if
I'm up against that guy.
What was his name? Gregory?
His best chance to take me out was
when he told me to turn around,
but he didn't take the shot.
So MAYBE he didn't want to, or maybe
he just hesitated. So I don't know!
Then just now, there WAS
a zombie in front of me.
Maybe he's the reason hunters are
supposed to wear orange vests.
Except I AM wearing orange,
so what the fuck?!
I thought he wouldn't try to kill me
at least until I completed his course,
but that would imply he's sane.
He could have competing
voices where one is saying,
"Wait for him to complete the course." And
the other is saying, "No! Kill him now!"
GRIGORI: Although they call me crazy--
OH!
GRIGORI: I care not, for thou art my
helper, my strength, and my savior.
That's right. Only gunshots
make the voices go away.
Well, he's not SO crazy
that he thinks he can take a shot
at me without plausible deniability.
He knows I'll kill him if he does that.
So, you know, neighbors.
So. What was going on here?
Was he studying them?
I bet he doesn't even
have any medical training.
He was just poking them with a
screwdriver, pretending he's a doctor.
Oh, for c...
Yeah, no. I've always wanted a
fan club, but not of YOU people.
I'm kind of insulted.
[explosion]
Apology accepted.
Oh! It's a long one. All right.
How did it catch on fire?
I didn't know these were incendiary.
I just sort of stole them.
I shouldn't tell Gregory about
this--he might get pissed.
This could be his private reserve.
He keeps them penned up in here until
he's ready to start his game show,
then lets them loose.
Maybe he really is wrangling
them and trucking them back here.
But that wouldn't change
the dynamics. Not really.
Because I was right. Of course.
Some of these things are going hungry.
Ah.
Some of those huggers were skinny.
Yeah, it's funny--they're facehuggers,
and I always thought that was the problem
with aliens: They're too good a predator.
They're smart, they breed fast, their blood
is acid... They would collapse the ecosystem.
[fast zombies yowling]
The fuck?
Okay, I'm impressed with his
show. This is like a circus act.
AH! GROSS!
AH!
I don't even know if this
is part of his show anymore.
Maybe.
Before, he was kind of funneling me.
Ehh...
[zombie growls]
Where is that?
I don't see it.
More hanging people.
Well, I guess I have some answers now.
Like why a body was tied up by the hip.
He's crazy.
Or why he's hoarding five washing
machines in a place with no hookups.
He's crazy.
That's kind of disappointing, though,
that there's no pattern or meaning.
It's just some crazy guy?
It's kind of like when movies make stuff
up, then they say it was all a dream.
You're not.
If this was a dream, the
zombies would've turn to Jell-O,
and when Greg talked, his head would've
floated off because it was a balloon.
Well, not THAT way.
Fuck...
Nyehhh! I WANT THE AMMO!
[incoherent yelling]
I'M ACTUALLY GETTING A LITTLE LIGHT
ON BULLETS! I'M NOT PROUD OF THAT!
BLAH! COME ON WITH THE--
Fuck...
THIS IS NOW OFFICIALLY WORSE
THAN MY OLD APARTMENT BUILDING!
WE'VE CROSSED THAT LINE!
This isn't a dream!
Close the door!
GRIGORI: Here, brother!
Oh boy...
GRIGORI: Come closer.
I'm on a ledge.
GRIGORI: You've stirred up hell!
Yeah, yeah.
GRIGORI: A man after my own heart.
GRIGORI: Here, I have a
more suitable gun for you.
GRIGORI: You'll need it.
Don't do it!
GRIGORI: Catch!
Oh!
GRIGORI: Good. Now keep it close.
You're a good neighbor.
GRIGORI: My advice to you
is... aim for the head.
Yeah, I think--
GRIGORI: Hush.
Okay...
GRIGORI: They come.
GRIGORI: There is no rest in Ravenholm.
Uh...
GRIGROI: Move on and I will...
Shells, too!
You're the nicest person I've met today!
GRIGORI: Woe betide thee...
Why are these things so amped
up? What are you feeding them?
Come on. Get indoors. You're
still crazy. You'll catch a cold.
Yeah, okay!
See, that was a little close.
You still have no concept of "line of fire".
Did you used to be a cop or something?
Yeah, NOW he's gone. Right.
So where does he expect me to go?
Well, he didn't leave a pair of
homemade wings, so that's a positive.
Oh no. No.
No, come on.
He wants me to jump in the
dunk tank like a clown?
Is he trying to say I'm the clown?
I am wearing bright colors.
Fuck.
I didn't think of it. I should've
checked inside those washers.
I give a 50-50 chance he
has human heads in there.
Maybe entire bodies.
He has to wash the sin out.